世界变为火车那年我十岁
I was ten when the world became a train.
威尔福德说他现在是我的家人
Wilford said he was my family now.
达布斯爸爸
Daddy Dubs.
我会跟他一起领导列车
And I would lead the train with him.
领袖很孤单
Leaders were lonely.
你不能信任任何人
You couldn't trust anyone.
于是我一个人住在艾莉克斯的孤岛上  从未有人造访
So I was the island of Alex, and no one ever came ashore.
直到我们终于追上梅兰妮
Until we finally caught up to Melanie...
我看到了雪国列车  认识了她的人
And I saw Snowpiercer and met her people.
达布斯在这时也变得奇怪起来
That's when Dubs got weird.
你知道"乌布里耶"是什么吗
Do you know what an oubliette is?
法国地牢
A French dungeon.
一个特别的地下密牢  天花板上有个小孔
A special dungeon underground with a tiny hole in the roof.
他们把你永久关在里面  意味着忘记
They just drop you in forever. It means forget.
梅兰妮  莱顿
Melanie, Layton,
把他们都关进地牢  好吗
drop them all in the oubliette, eh?
你不想要我忘记他们
You don't want me to forget them.
你想让我和他们断绝关系
You want me to renounce them.
准备好后来前车
Uptrain when you're ready.
一开始  我以为我妈妈和她的人
At first, I thought my mom and her people
愚蠢和杂乱无章
were stupid and disorganized,
但现在我觉得自由也许必须混乱
but now I think freedom probably has to be messy.
我在那边看到莱顿通过倾听他人来领导
Over there, I saw Layton lead by listening to others.
我看到了掌权的女性
I saw women with power.
我还看到他们让我妈妈的梦想不死
And I saw them keep my mother's dream alive.
-我们的朋友很小心啊  -嗯
- Our friend is quite careful. - Yeah.
我们的出路就靠他了
Well, our way out is through him.
今晚  如果我们还想跟梅兰妮对接的话
Tonight, if we're gonna have any shot of getting back to Melanie.
让我们走到了今天的高品质
Qualities that got us this far
不会让我们通过威尔福德这关
won't get us past Wilford.
要想打败那样的人
To best a man like that...
你得变得残酷无情
you need to be utterly ruthless.
我们都做过可怕的事
We've both done terrible things.
还不够可怕
Not terrible enough.
我有个邪恶行凶的计划  让我们逃出这里
Well, I've got a foul and murderous plot to get us out of here,
如果您想从那开始的话
if you'd like to start there.
我愿意
I would.
我观察过威尔福德
I've watched Wilford.
见过他试图杀死我们所有人
Seen him take it right up to the edge of killing us all,
所以问题不是
so the question is not,
你愿意堕落到他的水平吗
"Are you willing to sink to his level?"
而是  你愿意赌上一切吗
It's, "Are you willing to risk everything?"
为了雪国列车和梅兰妮
For Snowpiercer and for Melanie...
为了一切
Everything.
总有一天  我会打破循环
One day, I'll break the cycle...
我们会一起离开雪国列车
and we'll walk away from Snowpiercer together,
1034节车厢
1,034 cars long.
雪国列车
第二季 第十集[季终]
"白茫茫的世界"
收盘子了
Tray!
能再给我点吗
Can I have some more?
拜托了
Please?
铲子  在沟渠里很好用
Shovel, it's good in the trenches.
你可以带上
You can bring it with you.
我们去找哈维吧
Let's go find Javi.
人都哪去了
Where is everybody?
这里是火车头
Oh, this is the engine.
我们需要再上一层
Now we need to go one more up.
露丝
Ruth?
我的天
Oh, my God.
艾莉克斯
Alex.
我们刚得知  你妈妈还活着
We've just found out. Your mum, she's alive.
我就知道  我就知道
I knew it. I knew it.
她在那  她在等我们
She's there. She's waiting for us.
我们要偷走大爱丽丝  然后去接她
We're gonna steal Big Alice and go get her.
用铲子吗
With a shovel?
任何协助都不胜感激
Well, any assistance would be appreciated.
火车头和威尔福德卧室之间有个秘密入口
How about the engine has a secret entrance to Wilford's bedroom?
好的  她也加入了
All right, she's in.
我们今天要穿过落基山脉旧测试轨道
We're crossing the Rocky Mountain Test Track today.
我们需要两辆车都在那转弯
We need both engines to make that turn.
好  所以我们还需要本
Okay, so we'll need Ben too,
但先把你救出来吧
but let's get you out of here first.
不用  我自己可以出去
No, I can get myself out of here.
威尔福德想要我臣服
Wilford wants me to kiss the ring.
我可以让凯文带我去见他
I can get Kevin to take me to him.
好  那秘密入口在哪
Okay. So about the secret entrance?
奥德丽
Audrey?
奥德丽  今天只有我工作吗
Audrey, am I the only one working today?
但你是只早鸟  对吗  贝丝
You're an early riser, though, aren't you, Bess?
还是夜行者  我喜欢有这种品质的顾问
And a night prowler. I like that in an advisor.
如果你不肯听我建议的话  我就算不上是你顾问
I'm not your advisor if you won't listen to my advice.
扎拉要来吗
Is Zarah coming around?
她拒绝了晚餐
She physically rejected dinner
还用叉子威胁我
and threatened me with a fork.
如果我们让她做列车之声呢
What if we offered her Voice of the Train?
你把莱顿关着  就休想收买她
You're not gonna buy her with Layton in your gulag.
我可以说服她
Well, she'd do it with convincing.
我很乐意掌掴她
I'd happily slap her.
我刚为什么那么做
Now, why did I do that?
冲动控制障碍
Poor impulse control?
还因为在雪国列车上
And because pregnancy
怀孕享有特权
comes with privilege on Snowpiercer.
没错  扎拉有特权
Exactly. Zarah's privileged.
她有着那不可言喻的莱顿"蜂王浆"
She has that ineffable royal Layton jelly.
凯文  我们想要这个
Kevin, we want some of that.
蜂王浆  我的错  先生
Royal jelly. My mistake, sir, of course.
出什么问题了  乔
What's going sideways now, Joe?
以毒攻毒  奥德丽  该扮演产妇了
Hair of the dog, Audrey. Time to play doula.
扎拉
Ugh, Zarah.
-继续  -等等
- Keep going. - Wait a minute.
我不信任他们  他们有点疯
I don't trust them. They're kind of crazy.
跟他们待在一起
Stay with the little guys.
我的天  天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
-冷静  -我的天
- Calm down. - Oh my God.
深呼吸
Deep breath.
只是乘客服务部杀了一个人而已
It's just hospitality killing a man.
你联系了我们  对吗
You called us, yeah?
天呐  成功了  你们收到了纸条
Holy shit, it worked. You guys got the note?
我们成功了  你身上一股屎味儿
We did it. Ugh, you smell like crap.
我们知道  我们现在在哪
Yeah, we know. Where are we?
两小时后到转弯处
We're two hours from the turn.
我们必须成功转弯
We have got to make that turnoff.
艾莉克斯也加入了我们
Alex is with us too.
她在前车帮我们迷惑威尔福德
She's running interference on Wilford uptrain.
给
Here.
得让本知道我们准备好接上梅兰妮了
We need to let Ben know we're ready to pick up Melanie.
很好  我们该怎么做
Great, okay. How do we do that?
给我点时间  拜托
Just give me a moment. Please.
肯定会很糟糕
Oh, this is gonna be bad.
你看这里的东西
Look at all of this, eh?
威尔福德先生在这过得挺舒适啊
It's a nice life Mr. Wilford's got for himself back here, eh?
属于他的小宫殿
His own little palace.
老天爷
Christ almighty.
你先  露丝
After you, Ruth.
好
Okay.
现在晃动手指
Now wag it.
-毫不费力  -好
- Easy. - Okay.
-摇滚  -现在转动手腕
- Rock and roll. - Now wrist spin.
好
Yeah.
嗯  你做得很好
Okay, yeah, you're getting pretty good.
你觉得在外面能正常运作吗
Do you think it'll work outside?
就是设计成在室外使用的
It's designed to.
他们说你是新的冰鲍勃
They say you're the new Icy Bob.
我差点在严寒中冻死
I was nearly killed in the cold.
出事的时候  我感觉到皮肤裂开
When it happened I felt my skin crack,
拉扯
and stretch,
没错  我当时害怕极了
and, yeah, I was really scared.
但现在
But now?
现在  我想到外面去
Now, I want to go out there,
想看看我有何能耐
want to see what I can do.
梅兰妮离开去做徒劳无益的事了
Melanie left on a fool's errand.
又来了
Again?
她离开就是犯蠢
She was a fool to leave.
她的团队应当受到她的惩罚  我也是
Her team deserved her punishment, and so did I.
你觉得她说的是真心话吗
Does she sound sincere to you?
我相信是
I believe so.
我是真心感到抱歉  约瑟夫
I am sorry, Joseph.
晚饭时我不该说那些话的
I shouldn't have said that stuff at dinner,
我也一定会向奥德丽小姐道歉的
and I'll make sure to apologize to Miss Audrey, as well.
-你回来了  -是的
- Oh, you're back. - Yes.
我回来了  小莱  希望你也能原谅我
Yes I am, LJ, and I was hoping that you could forgive me too.
好吧
Okay.
我从三等厢带了食物回来当早餐
I brought some treats from third class for breakfast.
莱顿会来  我们要占领车头
Layton is coming, and we're seizing the engine.
赛克斯时刻待在他旁边
Sykes is with him every minute.
那"我们要偷走列车"的暗号是什么
Okay, so what's code for "we're stealing the train?"
我和那家伙相处了八年
I've spent eight years with the guy.
他现在应该能听懂我的暗示
He should be able to figure me out by now.
雪国列车  这里是大爱丽丝
Snowpiercer, this is Big Alice.
-请说  大爱丽丝  -今天挺忙  对吧  本
- Come in, Big Alice. - Busy day, Ben, huh?
-是吗  -会忙起来的
- Is it? - It will be.
到山上你们会有颠簸
You're gonna get bumpy up there.
激光雷达显示会有轨道障碍物
Lidar's showing track obstructions
北纬52度  58分35秒
at north 52 degrees, 58 minutes, 35 seconds,
西经119度  25分28秒
west 119 degrees, 25 minutes, 28 seconds.
-我得核对下  -麻烦反复核对
- I have to check something. - Yes, double-check please.
-呼叫大爱丽丝  坐标已记下  -很好
- Calling Big Alice. Coordinates have been noted. - Good, good.
记住  我们这能控制  知道吗
Just know we've got control back here okay?
好的  我们会做好准备
All right. We'll prepare to brace.
好的  做好准备
Affirmative. Prepare to brace.
接近时再联系你
I'll get back to you on approach.
他听懂了  我知道
He got it. I know he did.
-你准备好干活了吗  哈维  -我可以撑足够久
- You ready to dig in, Javi? - I can hold it long enough.
你很勇敢  德拉托雷先生
You're a brave man, Mr. De la Torre.
别这么说  让我很紧张
Don't say that. It makes me nervous.
我们在边境仍有朋友
Still, we've got our friends at the border
需要带你们去前车
that need to get you uptrain.
-谢谢你  -祝好运
- Thank you. - Good luck.
-都上车了吗  -扶好
- All aboard? - Hold fast.
瞧  双蛋黄
Look, a double yolk.
司闸员博斯科维奇  见到你真高兴
Breachman Boscovic, what a welcome sight.
哥们
Hey, man.
-见到你真好  兄弟  -车尾情况如何
- It's good to see you, bro. - How's the Tail?
仍然坚守着这一区
Still hanging on to the neighborhood.
你能相信吗
Do you believe this?
我和车尾联手  因为混蛋威尔福德
Me with Tail because son of a bitch Wilford?
混蛋威尔福德会大发雷霆
Well, son of a bitch Wilford is gonna blow a head gasket.
这是嘉年华会吗
Is this a carnival?
我们要回去接梅兰妮
We're going back for Melanie.
你想走落基山脉测试轨道
You want to take Rocky Mountain Test Track.
没错
That's bloody right.
-你能守住车中段的一个冷锁处吗  -当然
- Can you secure a cold lock mid-train? - Da.
好极了  我们可以把梅兰妮带回这里
Oh, perfect. We can bring Melanie back here.
让她向民众发表讲话
We can put her on the public address,
这样整辆列车都会知道她还活着
and the whole train will know she's alive.
好的  我们去发动政变吧
Okey dokey, let's go make coup.
你们听见他说的了  我们去发动政变
You heard the man. Let's go make coup.
我本来想给你一杯的
I'd offer you one,
但他会说个没完
but I'd never hear the end of it.
约瑟夫认为一小口酒就会把胎儿变成蝌蚪
Joseph thinks one sip would turn the fetus into a tadpole.
他对你感兴趣
He's taken an interest in you.
你应该把这看作好事
You should see that as a good thing.
我都不认得你了
I don't even recognize you.
我是想帮你
I am trying to help you.
你以为你有筹码  其实你没有
You think you have leverage, but you don't.
他不需要你  扎拉  只需要你的子宫
He doesn't need you, Zarah, just your womb,
海德伍德夫妇可以把你剔除出去
and the Headwoods can take you right out of the equation.
奥德丽  你不必当他的走卒
Audrey, you don't have to be his pawn.
老天
Oh, Christ.
我们现在处境相同  一向如此
We are the same as we always have been.
就是生存  生存  生存
Survive, survive, survive.
什么事
What do you want?
我去  贝丝
Oh, shit. Bess?
莱顿马上就来
Layton's coming.
我想我们要攻占火车头
I think we're seizing the engines.
-什么  -帮我
- What? - Help me.
来
Come on.
拜托  我要拿些地图
Come on. I need to get some maps.
我要拿些地图
I need to get some maps.
要地图做什么  用卫星就好了
Since when? Use the satellite.
不行  这里信号不好
Well, no, the reception's degraded here.
我需要拿些纸  能让我去拿地图吗
I need to get some paper. Please can I just get the map?
别做傻事
Now, don't do anything stupid, all right?
我不想伤害你
I don't want to hurt you.
你有用过这个吗
You ever used one of those?
-这是棒球棒  -我来教你
- It's a bat. - I'll show you.
警告
哈维  结束了  我们转弯了
Javi, it's done. We made the turn.
祝你好运  本
Buena suerte, Ben.
雪国列车火车头  请回话
Snowpiercer engine, come in.
莱顿  我们马上要到达汇合地点了
Layton, we're climbing up to the pickup location.
十分钟之内应该就能到达研究站
Should reach the research station in about ten minutes.
我们现在在冷锁处
We're in position in the cold lock.
做好准备
Standing by.
你觉得威尔福德不会发现你转弯了吗
You don't think Wilford's gonna notice you made that turn?
-闭嘴  -那是试验轨道
- Be quiet. - It's test track.
很崎岖  他会感觉到的
It's rough. He's gonna feel it.
哈维  我要加速攀爬
Javi, I'm accelerating for the climb.
稳稳地
Nice and easy.
谢谢
Thank you.
艾莉克斯
Alex?
我去检查一下火车头
I'll check with the engine.
火车头  你好
Hello, engine.
威尔福德想问问你们的情况
Wilford would like to check your status.
艾莉克斯你好
Hello, Alex.
-他在监视你吗  -是的
- Is he watching you? - Affirmative.
别让他闲着
Keep him occupied.
-我们很快就好  -收到
- We won't be much longer. - Roger that.
雪崩残骸  不用担心
Avalanche debris. Nothing to be worried about.
我见过你母亲这么做
You know, I saw your mother do that.
打给火车头
Call ahead to the engine.
耍诡计
A ruse.
两个引擎室都派人去  做好攻入的准备
You, send men to both engines ready for forced entry.
我会在大爱丽丝负责指挥  带上她一起
I'll command from Big Alice. Bring her with us.
他知道了  太早了
He knows. It's too soon.
他们来了  哈维
Here they come, Javi.
现在我们只能拖延他们
Now we just gotta hold them off.
你倒是说得轻松
Yeah, It's easy for you to say.
你们的车门比我的要厚
Your door's thicker than mine.
无论如何
Whatever happens,
你是个优秀的工程师  朋友
you are one hell of an engineer, my friend.
世界前三对吧
Top three in the world, right?
把她给我带走
Get her out of my sight!
拜托  拜托
Come on. Come on.
拜托
Come on.
把切割刀拿来
Get a cutter.
把我的狗带过来
And fetch my dog.
我们过了汇合地点
We've passed the pickup location.
没看到梅兰妮
There's no sign of Melanie.
我们不是很准时
We're not exactly on time.
给她个机会  她会来的
Give her a chance. She'll be here.
我已经把车速减到每小时25公里了
Okay, I've slowed down to 25 kilometers an hour.
你到了汇合地点  我会再减速
I'll slow further once you reach the pickup location.
-仔细留意  -拜托
- Keep your eyes peeled. - Come on.
乖狗狗
Good girl.
拜托
Come on please.
拜托  拜托
Come on please. Come on please.
雪国列车  能听到吗
Snowpiercer, do you hear me?
那里  她在那里
There! There she is!
还来得及  我看到她了
It's not too late. I see her!
好  好
Okay, okay.
拜托
Come on.
不
No!
好
Yeah.
住手  住手
Stop, stop!
你不能杀我  你需要工程师
You can't kill me. You need engineers.
咬他
Attack!
停下
Stop.
我们在加速
We're speeding up.
你们要减速  听到了吗
You need to slow your roll. Do you hear me?
减速
Stop!
哈维  减速  你开得太快了
Javi, slow down. You're going too fast.
哈维
Javi.
哈维  听到了吗
Javi, do you read me?
哈维
Javi!
不  班尼特  是我
No, Bennett. It's me.
你尽管刹车吧  孩子
You can brake all you want, son,
但我的转力更多  势头也在我这儿
but I've got more torque, and I've got momentum.
只要把你推过那山脊  剩下的就靠地心引力了
Just push you over that crest and let gravity do the rest.
停车  停车
Stop, stop, stop!
刹车撑不住的  已经过热了
The brakes can't handle this. We're overheating.
快啊  爱丽丝
Come on, Alice.
我拖不住了
I can't hold her!
他会把我们推过山脊的
He's gonna push us over the crest.
妈  妈
Mom! Mom!
妈  不要
Mom, no!
再见
See ya.
妈
Mom!
请把火车调头
Please turn the train around.
她没死  她掌握了科学
She survived, and she has the science.
太好了  我们就当这些都是科学吧
Yes, let's do pretend this is all about science.
人们有权知道她发现了什么
The people deserve to know what she discovered.
这是个闹剧  白日梦
It's a folly, a fantasy!
她无法接受我救了她  救了你
She could not accept the truth that I saved her life,
救了所有人的事实
and yours, and everyone's!
看着你们相信她的把戏  我心碎难当
It breaks my heart to see you fall for her games,
但是在这一切之后  你更像她而不是我
but after everything, you're so much more her than me.
不是  我两个都像
That's not true. I'm both.
不  不
No, no.
你只是我在路上顺手捡来的工具罢了
You're just a tool I collected on the way.
别这么说
Don't say that!
一点小伎俩就把你母亲引出来了
A handy little lever to pry your mother out,
你做了你该做的事
and you did your job.
现在你可以加入她
Now you can join her trackside.
你永远也不可能成为她那样的领袖
You could never be the leader she is!
好了  放松
Here we go. Take it easy.
放松
Take it easy.
别躺下  别躺下
Get up. Get up.
别躺下  好了
Get up. Here we go.
我们要消毒伤口
We need to disinfect the wound.
-好  -好
- All right. - Okay.
-抓住那个小兔崽子  -我来看看
- Just staunch the bugger. - Let's have a look.
我来看看
Have a look.
我们要缝合伤口  把手放下来
We're gonna stitch this up. Let's take the hand down.
很好  现在我们要...
Good, now, we're gonna--
尽量不要动
try to stay very still.
-没事的  -好  好
- It's all right. - Good, good.
天呐
God.
好了  好了  好了
Okay, okay, there. There you go, okay.
警告
不许进入
天呐
Jesus!
-是你  -你回来了
- It's you. - You made it back.
我们要找到露丝  看看下一步该怎么做
We're going to find Ruth to figure out what to do next.
莱顿  还有办法救梅兰妮
Layton, there's still a way to save Melanie.
边走边说
Tell us on the way.
你们想切断雪国列车的火车头吗
You want to cut Snowpiercer's head off?
艾莉克斯来说
Alex.
我们开走火车头
Well, we'll take the engine
和几节列车一起去找梅兰妮
along with a string of cars for Melanie.
速战速决  把她带回来和列车重接在一起
We'd be quick, and we would bring her back to reconnect.
就这样不管所有的人吗
And just leave everyone?
大爱丽丝有足够的能量维持系统
Big Alice has enough juice for systems to survive.
威尔福德会被阻碍
Wilford'll be hobbled.
那辆火车又笨重又慢  我们能以策略制胜
That's a big, slow train we can outmaneuver.
好吧  但我们不能在封锁的时候分离
Right, but we can't decouple on lockdown.
是的  链接是固定关闭的
Da, J-links are fixed closed,
但我们有一节列车可以手动超控
but we have one car with manual override.
水族馆  薄弱环节
The aquarium-- a weak point
即使在封锁状态也可以丢弃
designed to be jettisoned even on lockdown.
从那断掉  我们就能获得一辆十节车厢的探险火车
Break it there, we got a ten-car pirate train.
好了  好了
All right, all right.
There we are. There we are.
在边境集合  给我行动
Form up at the border. Move!
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
我们要前后彻底搜查列车
We'll search the train back to front.
去吧  女人  今天轮到你发挥作用了
Go, woman. It's your big day.
你要帮我把我的火车头夺回来
You're gonna get me my engine back.
我要你朝前走  进入火车头
I want you to go forward, breach the car,
把本的蛋蛋给我冻僵
and freeze Ben's balls solid.
长官  她还没准备好
Sir, she is nowhere near ready for that.
她这样走进去会死的
She'll never survive a walk of that--
那我们要她来干什么
Then why did we make her?
把她带去前车
Get her uptrain...
把舱口锁住
And lock the hatch.
如果你想回来  就要从火车头回来
If you want back in, it's through the engine.
马上去
Right away.
如果我们现在不夺取新伊甸园  一切就完了
If we don't make a play for New Eden right now, that's it.
结束了  就是威尔福德的天下了
It's gone. It is Wilford's world.
那样我们会让所有人都受他摆布
We'd be leaving everyone at his mercy.
我们有保险
We've got insurance.
好极了  奥德丽是人质吗
Great. Audrey's the hostage?
我们要救回我们真正想要的人吗
Are we bringing anyone we actually want?
是的  本  艾莉克斯和波吉
Yes, Ben, Alex, Boki.
那是两位工程师和一位维修工
That is two Engineers and a Breachman,
露丝现在会在水族馆和我们汇合
and Ruth is meeting us at the aquarium now.
-你太乱来了  -没错
- You're way off-book. - Yeah, I am.
抱歉  但我现在要赌上一切
I'm sorry, but I'm all in right now.
妈的
Shit.
我也是
I am too.
有我们的孩子在  安德烈  我做不到
With our child, Andre, I'm not.
我在这里更安全
I'm safer here...
-扎拉  -和我们认识的魔鬼交手
- Zarah. - With the devil we know.
威尔福德知道了
Wilford knows.
我会让奥德丽准备好的
I'm gonna go get Audrey ready.
对不起  扎拉
I'm sorry, Zarah.
我不能把你丢在这里  这样不行
I can't leave you here, not like this.
拜托  你必须要跟我们走
Please, you have to come with us.
威尔福德尊重我
Wilford wants me on a pedestal.
我可以在他手下活下来
I can survive him.
你回来的时候  你会需要我在这的
And you're gonna need me here when you come back.
我会回来找你的  扎拉
I'm coming back for you, Zarah.
记住你的呼吸  保持冷静  慢慢移动
Now, remember your breathing. Stay calm and move slow.
-等一下  -不不不
- Wait, wait, wait! - No, no, no!
拜托  你说过我没准备好
Please, you said that I'm not ready.
照威尔福德的指令行事
Just follow Wilford's orders.
进入火车头  然后回来
Breach the engine and come back in.
我们会在这里给你治疗的
We will be here to patch you up.
-那是什么  -充气长矛筒
- What's that? - Pneumatic breach pike.
炸药装这里  这样准备
Charge goes in here. Arms like so.
撞击触发  你不会有事的
Triggers on impact. You'll be fine.
对不起
I'm sorry.
现在就看你的了  乔茜
It's in your hands now, Josie.
有人要出去了
Someone's going outside.
是威尔福德的冰女
That'll be Wilford's cold woman.
他一直在打造的那个车尾人
The Tailie that he's been working on.
你是说乔茜吗
You mean Josie?
她要进入火车头
She's coming to breach the engine.
她会杀了我们俩的
She's gonna kill us both.
她绝对不会这么做
She'd never do that.
乔茜  乔茜  你听到了吗
Josie. Josie, do you read me?
是谁
Who is this?
我是雪国列车首席工程师
I'm the head engineer of Snowpiercer.
我控制着火车头
I have control of the engine.
我们需要你的帮助
We're gonna need your help.
站住
Stop.
好
All right.
你著名的军队呢
Where's your famous army?
-我不是来打仗的  -不是吗
- I'm not here to fight. - No?
这是你的对话斧头吗
This your conversation axe, is it?
火车头  开启第一个超驰控制
Engine, unlocking first override.
收到  波吉
Copy, Boki.
莱顿会尽量拖住他们
Layton will hold them off as long as he can.
我就说我闻到了粪便的味道
I thought I smelled compost.
我们要回去接梅兰妮
We are going back for Melanie.
你错过机会了  孩子  梅兰妮已经被甩开了
You missed your chance, son. Melanie's long behind us.
-你不准过来  -不  我不会的
- You're not coming. - No, no, I'm not.
去吧
All right, go on.
快去
Go on. Go on.
放我出去
Let me out.
制服给我  不然我就要来硬的了
Give me the teals, or we do it the hard way.
好  好  你赢了
All right, all right, you win.
不
No!
你要在我们走的期间放规矩一点
You're gonna behave yourself while we're gone.
不能复仇  不能报复
No vengeance. No reprisals.
不能碰这些人
You keep your hands off these people.
奥德丽
Audrey.
你决定了你的命运  贝丝·提尔
You've sealed your fate, Bess Till.
不是第一次了
Not the first time.
露丝没有赶到
Ruth never made it.
她是我们的抵押品  扎拉必须安全
She's our guarantee that Zarah stays safe.
退后
Step back!
所有人站到链条后面
Everyone get behind the link!
我的天  退后
My God, back.
艾莉克斯知道这里的J链
Alex knew all about the J-link here.
下面谁在用十字扳手
Who's downstairs with the lug wrench, eh?
波吉  回话
Boki, come in.
波吉  有收到吗
Boki, do you read me?
波吉
Boki!
波吉  有收到吗  那边什么情况
Boki, do you read me? What's going on down there?
水族馆
头等厢
你觉得我会让你断开我的火车头
You think I'd let you uncouple my engine?
退后  不然我杀了她
Get back, or I'll kill her!
-那就动手啊  -不
- Then do it. - No!
在上帝和所有鱼之前动手
Do it before God and all the fish.
-什么  -没事的  亲爱的
- What? - It's all right, darling.
我们都知道他不是那样的人
We all know by now it's not who he is.
你做得很好  继续
You're doing great. Keep going.
很好  乔茜  打破车厢
That's it, Josie. Breach the whole damn car!
该死
Shit.
只是天气
All right, it's just weather.
只是芝加哥天气
It's just Chicago weather.
还有山
With mountains.
谢谢你  艾莉克斯
Thank you, Alex.
是啊  还有山
Yeah, with mountains.
你现在对于志愿搜寻怎么想啊  莱顿
How do you feel about volunteering now, Layton?
太迟回不来让你替我了
Too late to come back and let you?
-恐怕是的  -他说  "恐怕是的"
- 'Fraid so. - He said, "Afraid so."
我们找到了梅兰妮的踪迹  要去走上一圈了  莱顿
We found Melanie's trail. Just going for a walk, Layton.
外出散步而已
Just out for a stroll.
这里面还能再热一点吗
Could it get any hotter in here?
我们现在是法拉利了
We're a Ferrari now.
只能热行
We're gonna run hot.
好极了
Great.
就快到了
We're almost there.
梅兰妮
Melanie!
妈
Mom!
现在是零下97度
It's minus-97 in here.
妈
Mom?
这里面更暖和
It's warmer in here.
还有电
Wow, there's power.
只是她的数据
Oh, it's just her data.
她让驱动器保持暖和
She kept the drives warm.
她没了
She's gone.
我们把这些东西装好  拿上雪撬
Let's pack this stuff up and get it on the sled, okay?
这是她想要的  她是为了我们这么做的  艾莉克斯
It's what she wants. She did it for us, Alex.
这里什么也没有
I had nothing here to return to.
我是凡人
I'm only human,
所以我当然用尽了资源
so of course I used up my resources.
把老鼠吃灭绝了
Ate my rats to extinction,
然后寒冷慢慢袭来
and the cold crept in.
剩下的电力最多能让我
There isn't enough power to keep me alive
多活几小时  但是在涓流充电上
more than a few hours, but on a trickle charge,
驱动器可以维持数月
the drives could last months for you.
当列车在火光中从我身边开过时
I knew when the train blew past in sparks and flame,
雪国列车刹车  大爱丽丝推行
Snowpiercer braking and Big Alice pushing,
我就知道威尔福德在设法搞破坏
that Wilford was sabotaging it all somehow.
但你在窗户那里  艾莉克斯
But you were there in the window, Alex.
我知道你会回来
I knew you'd come back.
我写下这段话的时候能感受到你在看
I can feel you reading this, as I write,
所以现在我可以戴上我的头盔
so now I can put on my helmet
安宁地走进茫茫白雪
and walk into the white at peace.
你是我的希望  艾莉克斯
You are my hope, Alex.
学会爱那些带我们走到今天的人
Learn to love the people that got us this far,
齐心协力  总有一天
and together, one day,
你们会创建一个更好的世界
you will build a better world.
她做到了
She did it.
这些是暖和的地方
These are warm places.
她牺牲好让我们能幸存
She did it so we could survive.
天呐  真美
my God. It's beautiful.
太美了
Absolutely beautiful.
小心
Heads up.
有恶劣天气要来了
We've got weather approaching.
我们去夺回我们的列车吧
Let's go get our train back.